Henry VIII had six wives. One survived.
Firebrand is a drama, history, thriller film directed by Karim Aïnouz.
Katherine Parr, the sixth wife of King Henry VIII, is
named regent while the tyrant battles abroad.
When the king returns, increasingly ill and paranoid, Katherine
finds herself fighting for her own survival.
Katherine Parr, played by Alicia Vikander.
Henry VIII, played by Jude Law.
Edward Seymour, played by Eddie Marsan.
Thomas Seymour, played by Sam Riley.
Stephen Gardiner, played by Simon Russell Beale.
Anne Askew, played by Erin Doherty.
Firebrand is a 2023 British historical drama film directed by Karim Aïnouz and written by Henrietta
Ashworth and Jessica Ashworth, based on the 2013 novel Queen's Gambit by Elizabeth Fremantle.
The film focuses on Catherine Parr, Queen of
England, the sixth wife of Henry VIII.
It stars Alicia Vikander, Jude Law, and Eddie Marsan.
The film marks Aïnouz's first directorial effort in the English language.
Firebrand premiered at the 76th Cannes Film Festival on 21 May
2023, where it was selected to compete for Palme d'Or.
It was released in the United Kingdom on 6 September 2024.
The film explores themes of based on novel or
book, henry viii, historical drama.
The tone is emotional and intense.